<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Prajwal Krishna</title>
    <link>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Prajwal Krishna</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 11:25:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Airline Passenger Satisfaction Prediction using Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/post/project-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/post/project-7/</guid>
      <description>Project Overview- The goal of this project is to develop a machine learning model that predicts passenger satisfaction based on various features and attributes related to airline services. We will explore, preprocess, visualize, and analyze the dataset before training and evaluating multiple machine learning models. This project is a practical demonstration of applying data science and machine learning techniques to solve a real-world problem in the airline industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LangChain Powered PDF Chat for Communication</title>
      <link>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/post/project-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/post/project-8/</guid>
      <description>Project Overview- Langchain-PDF-App-GUI Project Description: The project aims to develop a PDF querying system that leverages LangChain, a powerful language processing tool, to extract information from PDF documents. By employing LangChain&amp;rsquo;s advanced natural language understanding capabilities, the system will enable users to perform complex searches and obtain specific data points from PDF files efficiently and accurately.
Website https://github.com/praj2408/Langchain-PDF-App-GUI/assets/70437673/6f1f0806-f6d5-416d-9f6a-5c5282db2769
Features: PDF Parsing: The system will incorporate a PDF parsing module to extract text content from PDF files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adult Census Income Prediction</title>
      <link>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement: The Goal is to predict whether a person has an income of more than 50K a year or not. This is basically a binary classification problem where a person is classified into the &amp;gt;50K group or &amp;lt;=50K group.
Dataset Adult Census Income Dateset
The dataset used for this project is the Adult Census Income dataset. It contains information about individuals, such as age, workclass, education, marital status, occupation, relationship, race, gender, capital gain, capital loss, hours per week, and native country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consignment Pricing Prediction Using MLOps DVC</title>
      <link>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>Project Overview- The Consignment-Price Prediction project aims to develop a machine-learning model that can accurately predict the price of consignment items based on various features and variables. Consignment is a business model in which an individual or business agrees to sell someone else&amp;rsquo;s items on their behalf, typically taking a commission on the final sale price.
This project aims to create a predictive model to help consignment store owners and sellers better understand how to price their items, leading to increased sales and profits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jigsaw - Toxic Comment Classification Project</title>
      <link>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Project Overview The Toxic Comment Classification project is an application that uses machine learning to identify toxic comments. The application uses a dataset of comments from social media platforms, such as Twitter, to train a model that can detect toxic comments. The goal of the project is to develop a model that can accurately classify toxic comments and help moderators filter out comments that violate community guidelines.
Website Dataset The dataset used in this project is the Toxic Comment Classification Challenge from Kaggle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insurance Premium Prediction</title>
      <link>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Problem Analysis The goal of this project is to give people an estimate of how much they need based on their individual health situation. After that, customers can work with any health insurance carrier and its plans and perks while keeping the projected cost from our study in mind. This can assist a person in concentrating on the health side of an insurance policy rather than the ineffective part.
Website Link https://insurance-premium-price-prediction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text-Summarizer-Project</title>
      <link>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Description The Text-Summarizer-Project is an advanced natural language processing (NLP) application that aims to automatically generate concise summaries of large blocks of text. With the ever-increasing amount of information available online and in various documents, extracting key information efficiently has become a crucial task. This project addresses the need for effective and accurate text summarization by utilizing cutting-edge NLP techniques.
The primary objective of the Text-Summarizer-Project is to develop a robust and versatile system capable of summarizing a wide range of textual data, including articles, research papers, news reports, and other lengthy documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated-Machine-Learning-App</title>
      <link>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>The Automated ML WebApp project is a tool developed using Python, Pandas Profiling, PyCaret, and Streamlit frameworks. It aims to simplify and streamline the process of building machine learning models by automating various tasks involved in data preprocessing, feature engineering, model selection, and downloading the trained models.
Frameworks Used: Python The core of the web application is built using Python, a versatile programming language widely used in the field of data science and machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/about/</guid>
      <description>Illustration from Victor Hugo et son temps (1881) Hello there! I&amp;rsquo;m Prajwal Krishna, a passionate and dedicated aspiring data scientist. I&amp;rsquo;m on a mission to turn raw data into meaningful insights that drive informed decisions. With a recent completion of a Full Stack Data Science Masters from iNeuron Intelligence, I&amp;rsquo;ve armed myself with a comprehensive understanding of the data science landscape.
My journey into the world of data began with a fascination for its potential to revolutionize industries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m best reached via Email or LinkedIn. I&amp;rsquo;m always open to interesting conversations and collaboration.
Email: prajwalgbdr03@gmail.com
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/prajwalkrishna/
Github: https://github.com/praj2408
Lets Connect Your Name Email Address An email address is required. Message </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/coursework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://praj2408.github.io/Prajwal_Portfolio/coursework/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m best reached via Email or LinkedIn. I&amp;rsquo;m always open to interesting conversations and collaboration.
Email: prajwalgbdr03@gmail.com
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/prajwalkrishna/
Github: https://github.com/praj2408</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
